let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1.,
        question: 'What is the full form of IOT?',
        answer: 'C. Internet of Things',
        options: [
            'A. Internet of technology',
            'B. Incorporate of things',
            'C. Internet of Things',
            'D. internet of things'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2.,
        question: 'When was the actual term"Internet of things"conied? ',
        answer: 'B. 1999',
        options: [
            'A. 1998',
            'B. 1999',
            'C. 2000',
            'D. 2002'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3.,
        question: 'which of the following is not an Iot?',
        answer: 'A. BMP280',
        options: [
            'A. BMP280',
            'B. Smart home',
            'C. Smart city',
            'D. self-driven cars'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4.,
        question: 'which of the following is false about the IoT devices?',
        answer: 'B. A microphone is a digital sensor',
        options: [
            'A. A light sensor(photoresistor) is an analog sensor',
            'B. A microphone is a digital sensor',
            'C. A push buttom is a digital sensor',
            'D. A keyboard is a digital sensor'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5.,
        question: 'which of the following is not related to Arduino IDE Io T software?',
        answer: 'D. terminate',
        options: [
            'A. serial monitor',
            'B. verify',
            'C. upload',
            'D. terminate'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6.,
        question: 'Iot gateway must provide..........',
        answer: 'A. Protocol abstraction',
        options: [
            'A. Protocol abstraction',
            'B. Data storage',
            'C. Security with hardware',
            'D. Simple and fast installation'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7.,
        question: 'which of the following protocol is used to link all the devices in the Iot?',
        answer: 'D. TCP/IP',
        options: [
            'A. HTTP',
            'B. UDP',
            'C. NETWORK',
            'D. TCP/IP'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8.,
        question: 'SAAS stands for..........',
        answer: 'A. Software as a service',
        options: [
            'A. Software as a service',
            'B. service as a software',
            'C. service as a service',
            'D. software as a software '
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9.,
        question: 'UDP stands for........',
        answer: 'A. user datagram protocol',
        options: [
            'A. user datagram protocol',
            'B. user diagram protocol',
            'C. user detection protocol',
            'D. user datagram protocol'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10.,
        question: 'DNS stand for',
        answer: 'B. domain name system',
        options: [
            'A. determine name system',
            'B. domain name system',
            'C. device name system',
            'D. development name system'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11.,
        question: 'SOC stand for........',
        answer: 'A. system on chip',
        options: [
            'A. system on chip ',
            'B. system on change',
            'C. source on chip',
            'D. source on change'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12.,
        question: 'GPU stands for..........',
        answer: 'A. graphical processing unit',
        options: [
            'A. graphical processing unit',
            'B. generally processing unit',
            'C. graphically program unit',
            'D. general programing unit'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13.,
        question: 'The opreating frequency of Z_wave india is.........',
        answer: 'C. 865 2MHz',
        options: [
            'A. 20MHz',
            'B. 80MHz',
            'C. 865 2MHz',
            'D. none of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14.,
        question: 'The antenna in single UAV system is.......',
        answer: 'B. directional',
        options: [
            'A. omnidirectional',
            'B. directional',
            'C. bidirectional',
            'D. none of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15.,
        question: 'The scalability is limited in........system',
        answer: 'B. Multi UAV',
        options: [
            'A. Single UAV',
            'B. Multi UAV',
            'C. both 1 and 2',
            'D. None of the above'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16.,
        question: 'What is the Ardunio UNO?',
        answer: 'B. Hardware device',
        options: [
            'A. software',
            'B. Hardware device',
            'C. Network',
            'D. Protocol'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17.,
        question: 'Which one of the following protocol is light weight',
        answer: 'C. MQTT',
        options: [
            'A. IP',
            'B. HTTP',
            'C. MQTT',
            'D. CoAP'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18.,
        question: 'How many logic signals are there in the SPI protocol',
        answer: 'A. Five signals',
        options: [
            'A. Five signals',
            'B. six signals ',
            'C. nine signal',
            'D. Zero signal'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19.,
        question: 'What is the range of z-wave',
        answer: 'A. 30 to 100m',
        options: [
            'A. 30 to 100m',
            'B. 300 to 1000m',
            'C. 100 to 1000m',
            'D. only 10 m'
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20.,
        question: 'The IPV6 developed in........',
        answer: 'A. 1998',
        options: [
            'A. 1998',
            'B. 1980',
            'C. 2000',
            'D. none of the above'
        ]
    } 

]   